Pretoria, South Africa | www.linkedin.com/in/rejoiceymucheri | rejoiceymucheri@gmail.com | +27683509886

CAREER SUMMARY

I am a motivated cloud enthusiast who loves taking the initiative and seeking new challenges. Having had a successful 12-year career in Sales and Customer Success in which 6 of those years I worked as a Zonal Director of Sales and Operations, I have had a lengthy client-focused career. I am looking to use my experience to drive company goals by building scalable, highly available, and secure solutions on AWS. I have strong problem-solving skills and the ability to troubleshoot complex technical issues. I am highly motivated to continue learning and growing my skills in the field of cloud computing. I am excited to bring my knowledge and experience to a new team. Looking for opportunities as a Solutions Architect, Cloud Engineer, Cloud Architect, or Cloud Administrator.

EXPERIENCE

HANDS-ON PROJECTS

CLOUD RESUME CHALLENGE

Working on an ongoing project with regular milestones. To date, I have achieved the following:

- Written my CV in HTML, CSS and JS.
- Used Amazon S3 to host a static website as well as using HTTPS for security.
- Pointed a custom DNS domain name to the CloudFront distribution, making my resume accessible via my registered domain.
- A variety of services were used to complete the different milestones from frontend to backend development. A visitor counter was written in JavaScript and DynamoDB was used to retrieve and store the visitor counter.
- Created an API that accepts requests from my web app and communicates with the database.

I am continuing to work on the last part of the challenge which entails:

- Building a CI/CD pipeline for both my frontend and backend and IAC, this is so that I don't have to configure my resources manually each time.
- This ongoing project showcases my progress, which can be found on: https://cloudupwithree.com/

BUILDING CRUDDUR, A TRUE EPHEMERAL-FIRST MICRO-BLOGGING (TWITTER-LIKE) PLATFORM

This project is tagged AWS Cloud Project Boot Camp organized by AWS Community Hero, Andrew Brown of ExamPro. I am building a true-ephemeral micro-blogging platform like Twitter, called Cruddur. For this application the frontend application is written in JavaScript using React (functional components). The backend application is written in Python using Flask. The web application is deployed to AWS.

• This is an ongoing project with regular milestones, which can be found on my GitHub. https://github.com/CloudRiRi15/aws-bootcamp-cruddur-2023

PROFESSIONAL

UPWORK

Freelance AWS Instructor

Feb 2023 to Present

- Delivering AWS Technical training for Datanomics Technologies LLC to a cohort of over 30 students focusing on the AWS Well-Architected Framework and preparing them to take the AWS Solutions Architect exam.
- Developing AWS Cloud Fundamentals and Architecting Course content in line with the AWS Cloud Practitioner and AWS Solutions Architect Associate Exams.
- Performing AWS Lab Audits that the students use for learning to gain hands-on experience.

Pretoria, South Africa | www.linkedin.com/in/rejoiceymucheri | rejoiceymucheri@gmail.com | +27683509886

- Perform live demonstrations of AWS technologies using AWS services to solve different business case scenarios in line with AWS best practises.
- Training and Mentorship of students.

PRAESIGNIS

AWS ReStart Instructor

Oct 2022 - Feb 2023

- Trained an all-mothers cohort of 24 learners in an intensive 12-week Restart program.
- Used scenario-based activities facilitated through lab sessions, to solve real-life industry problems like networking and security, databases and storage among other things.
- 100% pass rate of the AWS Restart program with a class average score of 96.63%.
- 89.78% pass rate for the AWS Cloud Practitioner exam with the highest score of 892 and lowest score of 786, and a class average of 803.
- Trained and Mentored learners preparing them for a cloud career.
- Successfully trained and mentored 2 intern facilitators assigned to me, who have now gone
 on to handle their own cohorts as facilitators.

SAVRAC MOVEMENT

Freelancer Cloud Architect

Jan 2022 to Date

- Deployed the company's WordPress website to AWS.
- Migrated the company's files to Amazon S3 and S3 Glacier as they were running out of storage space on their local and external hard drives reducing costs by over R30 000.
- Created and setup the Company's new AWS account, using AWS IAM, I set up the company's security permissions and policies for Amazon S3 and the AWS environment.

MARLICOM WORLD INTERNATIONAL

Freelance Cloud Engineer

Jan 2020 to Date

- Hosted company's website on S3 while implementing a gradual migration to AWS.
- Worked with the client and over 50+ talent (ranging from musical artists, poets, models and actors), to build a secure network and storage for each artist's project using IAM and S3 and DynamoDB.
- Created the company's database for the different projects using DynamoDB reducing operational overhead by more than 90% allowing the company to focus on building their product, this has resulted in the company taking on about 3 times more projects in the past year.
- Monitoring cloud usage and costs. Providing recommendations to optimize cloud spending helping the company reduce cloud costs.
- Maintain documentation on the cloud environment, including infrastructure design, policies, procedures, and configuration settings.

LOVEWORLD INCORPORATED JAN 2010 - JAN 2021

Zonal Director of Sales and Operations

Jan 2015 - Jan 2021

- Responsible for the planning, strategizing, organizing, and directing of all activities in the assigned Region bringing in over R12M in income annually.
- Budget Control and Profit and Loss Management.
- Using excel for Sales Data Analysis, and preparing sales forecasts and annual reports for management and stakeholders.
- Developed structures & systems and executed strategies that guaranteed more than 21% growth in monthly sales.

Pretoria, South Africa | www.linkedin.com/in/rejoiceymucheri | rejoiceymucheri@gmail.com | +27683509886

- Directly managed a cross-functional team of 28 in 7 countries, (SA, Namibia, Angola, Thailand, Madagascar & Reunion Island) ranging from entry-level administrators to senior sales managers, and collaborated with marketing, data analysis & business development.
- Initiated "Meet the Director Week" which focused on employees' well-being and growth by visiting different branches, resulting in a 61% increase in employee productivity, and provided regular job performance feedback increasing the team's output by 28% year over year.
- Exceeded annual income target goals by 20% in the first quarter of 2018, 2019, and 2020.
- Exceeded annual sales and income targets by over 38% in the past 6 years, with 3 of those years exceeding annual target income within the first quarter.
- Raised individual partners and clients from 5,400 to over 22,000 within a period of 5 years, by implementing a follow-up system that included cold calling and visitations campaigns, emails, and SMS tracking, resulting in an 87% increase in active monthly product users.

Head of Business Development & Customer Success

Jan 2012 - Dec 2014

- Spearheaded and significantly grew 4 new territories over 2 years resulting in 9 new branches, recruited & trained a new team of 18 sales reps, growing revenue by 51% in the first year representing 7% of the company income.
- Drove over R1,7 mil in expansion revenue for existing accounts by building relationships with account stakeholders, identifying expansion areas, and initiating the use of newly introduced networks within the organization.
- Hired and mentored a team of 25 sales and marketing staff.
- Conducted sales strategy and business development conferences and seminars for 150+ sales managers and associates across 5 countries.
- Brought back the company awarding and incentive system for compensation of both clients and employees resulting in a 31% increase in participation, creating new business leads, and signing up new clients.

Sales and Marketing Manager

Jan 2011 - Dec 2011

- Promoted to Sales, Marketing, and Business Development Manager within a year
- Working with a graphic designer and a developer, improved the in-house electronic portal for accountability of stock reducing manual work by over 60 hours monthly.
- Coached and taught 60+ sales associates in running the POS system, customer service practices, and opening and closing processes.
- Set up a resident call center network across 12 main branches with over 250 associates and 25 team leaders targeted at driving customer satisfaction and increased participation in loyalty programs, driving sales growth and customer base by over 36% & 78% respectively.

Administrative Manager

Jan 2010 - Dec 2010

- Cold calling and follow-up of old, new, and prospective clients, working with a team of 10 associates responsible for calling over 200 clients in a 6-hour shift each.
- Served as point of contact for customer resolution, successfully de-escalating 95% of issues without management involvement.
- Deposited cash to the bank, and helped the manager maintain accurate records and sales commission records for payroll.

WILFRAN WELDERS AND FENCING, KWEKWE, ZIMBABWE Trainee Manager

Nov 2008 - May 2009

 $\label{lem:pretoria} \textbf{Pretoria, South Africa} \mid \underline{www.linkedin.com/in/rejoiceymucheri} \mid \underline{rejoiceymucheri@gmail.com} \mid +27683509886$

- Handled merchandise returns, assisted manager in ordering new merchandise, and scheduled store associates to accept deliveries and transfer to stockroom and sales floor.
- Ensured all inventories on hand are handled properly, throughout the reconciliation process and month-end closing.
- Managed all reconciliation processes and stock-taking.
- Participated in meetings, workshops, and other learning opportunities.
- Following all company regulations, and health and safety codes.
- Learned about conflict resolution and sitting in on disciplinary hearings.

EDUCATION

University of the People, AmericaBachelor of Science, Computer Science

Currently Studying

University of South Africa, South Africa

Bachelor of Commerce in Management Accounting (Hons) Certified Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA) **Currently Studying**

CERTIFICATIONS & LICENCES

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
Microsoft Certified: Azure Solutions Architect Expert
Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate

N.B A full list of all my Certifications and Licences can be found on my Credly account. https://www.credly.com/users/rejoice-mucheri.defd7a02/badges